Finding Aid for Icie Gertrude Macy Hoobler Papers 1914-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Icie Gertrude Macy Hoobler Papers 1914-1979
Hoobler, Icie Gertrude Macy, 1892-
Research scientist. Correspondence, scientific reports and publications, other papers, and photographs, primarily concerning her interest in the problems of nutrition and aging, including her work with the Merrill-Palmer School in Detroit, the Detroit Institute of Cancer Research, the Children's Fund of Michigan, and Grand Valley State College in Allendale; also materials relating to her membership on the White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health, 1969, and various White House conferences on children and youth.
85209 Aa 2; UAm
29 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dr. Icie Macy Hoobler (donor no. 5043 ) and came to the library in two principal accessions, 1976 and 1982.
The collection is open for research.
Dr. Icie Macy Hoobler was born July 23, 1892 in Missouri but spent her professional life in Michigan. She was a graduate of Central College for Women (AB, 1914), the University of Chicago (BS, 1916), the University of Colorado (MA, 1918), and Yale University (Ph.D., 1920) with a degree in physiological chemistry. After earning her doctorate, Dr. Hoobler in 1923 joined the staff of the Merrill-Palmer School for Motherhood and Child Development. Her assignment was "to organize, equip and direct the Nutrition Research Project as a support to the teaching and training program." After consultation with school trustees and medical and service organizations, it was decided to place the Nutrition Research Laboratory in the Children's Hospital of Michigan. A cooperative arrangement was worked out whereby the school provided the finances and direction and the hospital provided the space, utilities, and medical guidance. Thus in late 1924, the Nutrition Research Laboratory of the Merrill-Palmer School and the Children's Hospital of Michigan was opened. Although the laboratory was in the vanguard in applying the new science of nutrition and child development, the school had limited resources and could not extend its work into other needed areas of research. Through the influence of the Detroit Pediatric Society, the laboratories and its resources were transferred in 1931 to the newly established charitable organization, the Children's Fund of Michigan. Dr. Hoobler continued on, assuming the position of director of the Fund's research division. The assured long time period of the fund and financial support permitted Dr. Hoobler to plan for extended studies on nutrition and the growth of children and on the metabolism of mothers. She continued with this work through the 25 years of the Fund's existence. In her career, Dr. Hoobler was acknowledged for her contributions in the field of maternal and child nutrition, as a scientist, researcher, and author. She died January 6, 1984.
The collection has been divided into the following series: Subject files (24.3 linear ft.); Lectures (0.7 linear ft.); Manuscripts of writings (0.5 linear ft.); Personal and Biographical Materials (2 linear ft.); and Published Materials (2 linear ft.). There are also three smaller series of genre materials: Photographs, Sound Recordings, and Artifacts.
Subjects:
Aging.; Children's Fund of Michigan.; Detroit Institute of Cancer Research.; Grand Valley State Colleges.; Hoobler, Icie Gertrude Macy, 1892-; Merrill-Palmer School.; Nutrition.; Old age.; Public health--Michigan.; White House Conference on Food, Nutrition, and Health (1969: Washington, D.C.); Women nutritionists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Youth--Michigan.; Nutritionists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Hoobler, Icie Gertrude Macy, 1892-; Merrill-Palmer School.; Women.
Subjects - Sound Recordings
Hoobler, Icie Gertrude Macy, 1892-; Physicians--Michigan.; Pilling, Patricia L.; Women physicians--Michigan.
Contributors:
Mendel, Lafayette B. (Lafayette Benedict), 1872-1935.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Subject files 1923-1976
  The largest series - Subject files (24.3 linear ft.;1923-1976) is an alphabetical arrangement of files containing correspondence, organizational affiliation materials, and other documents relating to her professional career and interests. As expected, the bulk of the Subject files fall within such headings as Aging and Gerontology, Children's Fund of Michigan, Grand Valley State College, the Merrill-Palmer School, and the National Research Council Committee on Maternal and Child Feeding and Food and Nutrition Board.
  - A (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
  - Abbott Laboratories (Box 1)
  - Adolph, William H. (Box 1)
  - Aging
    (see also Gerontology)
    - Ann Arbor Family Service Housing for the Aged (Box 1)
    - Association of Retired Persons-Drug Hearings 1959 (Box 1)
    - Citizens Advisory Committee to Michigan Commission on Aging (Box 1)
    - City of Detroit Committee on Aging (Box 1)
    - Committee on Aging, First Presbyterian Church, Ann Arbor (Box 1)
    - Detroit Synod Campaign (Box 1)
    - Governor's Commission on Aging 1959 (Box 1)
    - Lifelong Learning (Box 1)
    - Metropolitan Detroit Commission on Aging (Box 1)
    - Michigan Commission on Aging, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Michigan Conference on Aging (Box 1)
    - Ministries to the Aging-Presbyterian Church, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Presbyterian Church, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Presbyterian Village (Box 2)
    - Senior Citizens
      - Ann Arbor Senior Citizens Guild, 10 folders (Box 2)
      - Centers for Senior Citizens (Box 2)
      - Detroit (Box 2)
      - Flint (Box 2)
      - Legislation (Box 2)
      - Washtenaw Council on Aging (Box 2)
      - White House Conference on Aging 1959, 2 folders (Box 2)
      - White House Conference on Aging 1961 (Box 2)
  - Allen, Dr. Raymond B. (Box 3)
  - Alpha Nu (Box 3)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - American Association of Clinical Chemists (Box 3)
  - American Board of Clinical Chemistry (Box 3)
  - American Board of Nutrition (Box 3)
  - American Cancer Society (Box 3)
  - American Chemical Society
    - Biological Division (Box 3)
    - Biological and Medicinal Divisions (Box 3)
    - Committee on Publications (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, programs, reports (Box 3)
    - Detroit Section, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - Holmes, Dr. A. D. (Box 3)
    - Maynard, Dr. L. A. (Box 3)
    - Women in Chemistry (Box 3)
    - Women's (Garvan) Award, Fellowship Committee (Box 3)
    - Women's Committee, Women's Service Committee (Box 3)
  - American Congress of Obstetrics and Gynecology (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education (Box 3)
  - American Dental Association (Box 3)
  - American Dietetic Association (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Dietetic Association
    - Bulletins, Booklets (Box 3)
    - Committee on Dietary Study Methods (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Courier (Box 3)
    - Editorial Board (Box 4)
    - Mid-Century White House Conference on Children and Youth (Box 4)
    - Program Committee (Box 4)
    - Research Center Dietary Forms (Box 4)
  - American Food Journal (Box 4)
  - American Home Economics Association (Box 4)
  - American Home Economics Association 1962 Meeting (Box 4)
  - American Institute of Chemists (Box 4)
  - American Institute of Nutrition
    - Borden Award (Box 4)
    - Committee on Fellows (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence with non-members (Box 4)
    - Council Correspondence
      - 1935-1936 (Box 4)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 4)
    - Council Minutes and Proceedings (Box 4)
    - Council Reports, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
    - Discussion Groups (Box 4)
    - Du Bois, Dr. Eugene F. (Box 4)
    - Form Letters (Box 4)
    - General Council (Box 4)
    - Journal of Nutrition (Box 4)
    - Mead Johnson Award (Box 4)
    - Minimum Qualifications for Public Health Nutritionists (Box 4)
    - Murlin, John R. (Box 4)
    - Nutrition of Women in Relation to Motherhood, 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Osborne and Mendel Award (Box 5)
    - Presidency 1944-1945 (Box 5)
    - Programs and Proceedings (Box 5)
    - Questionnaire (Box 5)
  - American Journal of Clinical Pathology (Box 5)
  - American Medical Association, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - American Medical Association, Council on Scientific Research (Box 5)
  - American Pediatric Society (Box 5)
  - American Public Health Association
    - Committee on Child Health, 6 folders (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Papers (Box 5)
  - American Pure Food League (Box 5)
  - American Red Cross (Box 5)
  - American School Health Association (Box 5)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists (Box 5)
  - American Statistical Association (Box 5)
  - Antivivisection Committee (Box 5)
  - Archives of American Art, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor (Box 5)
  - Association of College Honor Societies (Box 6)
  - Association of Women in Science (Box 6)
  - B (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
  - Babbit, Ellen C. (Box 6)
  - Bay Cliff Study 1946 (Box 6)
  - Bayer and Bayley (Box 6)
  - Beach, Eliot F. (Box 6)
  - Biochemistry Congress (Box 6)
  - Block, Dr. Richard J. (Box 6)
  - Borden Milk Company
    - Infant Growth Study
      - 1933-1934 (Box 6)
      - 1935-1938 (Box 6)
    - Metabolic Studies of Children 1935-1938 (Box 6)
    - Study Report 1934 (Box 6)
  - Boys Republic Dietary Study (Box 6)
  - Brown, J. B. (Box 6)
  - C (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
  - Chemical Anthropology
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Reviews (Box 6)
  - Chicago Medical Society (Box 6)
  - Child Development and Welfare (Box 6)
  - Child Research Council (Box 6)
  - Children's Fund of Michigan
    - Annual Report of the Research Laboratory
      - 1931/32-1938/39, 8 folders (Box 6)
      - Summary Report 1931-1939 (Box 6)
      - 1939/40-1948/49, 10 folders (Box 6)
      - 1949/50-1952/53 (Box 7)
    - Budget of the Research Laboratory 1932-1950/51, 13 folders (Box 7)
      (some gaps)
    - Children's Center (Box 7)
    - Clinics
      - Central Michigan Clinic (Box 7)
      - Northern Michigan Clinic (Box 7)
    - Clippings (Box 7)
    - Closing of the Research Laboratory 1954 (Box 7)
    - Conference on Nutritional Status (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - First International Dietetic Congress 1952 (Box 7)
    - Maternal Blood Studies (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Programs (Box 7)
    - Research
      - Data Files (Box 7)
      - Projects (Box 7)
      - Publications, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Reviews and Editorials, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Sources of Funds (Box 7)
    - Staff (Box 7)
  - Children's Hospital of Michigan
    - Correspondence 1940-1974, 5 folders (Box 7)
    - Newsletter 1972-1974 (Box 8)
    - Pamphlets (Box 8)
    - Papers, Clippings (Box 8)
    - Reports, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Women's Auxiliary 1972-1975 (Box 8)
  - Clark, Leland C. (Box 8)
  - Colby, Dr. Martha G. (Box 8)
  - Connecticut Home Economics Association (Box 8)
  - Cornelian Corner, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Cornell University (Box 8)
  - Crampton, Dr. C. Ward (Box 8)
  - D (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
  - Darby, Dr. William J. (Box 8)
  - Day Care of Children (Box 8)
  - Detroit Board of Commerce (Box 8)
  - Detroit Dairy Council (Box 8)
  - Detroit Group Project (Clinical Group Work with Children) (Box 8)
  - Detroit Historical Society (Box 8)
  - Detroit Institute of Cancer Research
    - Affiliation with Wayne State University (Box 8)
    - Annual Reports
      - 1956 (Box 8)
      - 1957 (Box 8)
      - 1958 (Box 8)
      - 1966 (Box 8)
      - 1967 (Box 8)
    - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 8)
    - Joint Meetings (Box 8)
    - Meetings 1954-1955 (Box 8)
    - Merger into Michigan Cancer Foundation 1966 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Cancer Foundation, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Papers (Box 8)
    - Publications (Box 8)
    - Rehabilitation Series (Box 8)
    - Scientific Advisory Committee 1970 (Box 8)
    - Trustees 1946-1976, 22 folders (Box 9)
  - Detroit Nutrition Committee, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Detroit Physiological Society, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Detroit Science Center (Box 9)
  - Detroit Science Museum Society (Box 9)
  - Detroit Section-American Chemical Society (Box 9)
  - Dieckmann, Dr. William J. (Box 9)
  - Diet and Nutrition (Box 9)
  - Dietary Studies (Box 9)
  - Dietetic Congress (Box 9)
  - Donelson, Eva (Box 9)
  - E (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
  - Eppright, Mrs. Ercel S. (Box 10)
  - Escudero, Pedro (Box 10)
  - Evaporated Milk Association
    - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Public Education Committee (Box 10)
    - Public Information Committee (Box 10)
    - Public Relations Committee (Box 10)
  - Fels, Samuel S. Fund and Research Institute (Box 10)
  - Ford, Henry Hospital (Box 10)
  - Forms of other Nutrition Workers (Box 10)
  - G (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
  - General Education Board (Box 10)
  - Gerontology
    - International Association of Gerontology 1960 (Box 10)
    - Michigan Society of Gerontology
      - Correspondence 1956-1958 (Box 10)
      - Newsletters, Announcements (Box 10)
      - Publications 1968-1976 (Box 10)
      - 13th Annual Conference 1960, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Social Gerontology (Box 10)
  - Gesell, Dr. Arnold (Box 10)
  - Grand Valley State College
    - Administrative (Box 10)
    - Alumni Constitution (Box 10)
    - Association of Governing Boards of State Universities (Box 10)
    - Board of Control 1960-1965, 6 folders (Box 10)
    - Buchen, Philip W. (Box 11)
    - Challenges of Grand Valley State College (Box 11)
    - Citizen's Council (Box 11)
    - Clippings (Box 11)
    - College Site Committee (Box 11)
    - Con-Con Educational Committee on Behalf of Grand Valley State College (Box 11)
    - Contest on Name of College (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1968-1969 (Box 11)
    - Council on Basic Education (Box 11)
    - Educational Consultants (Box 11)
    - Founding Meetings (Box 11)
    - Fraternities (Box 11)
    - Lanthorn (College Newspaper) (Box 11)
    - Michigan Coordinating Council for Public Higher Education, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Michigan Council of State College Presidents, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - News Releases
      - 1961-1963 (Box 11)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 11)
      - 1972-1974 (Box 11)
    - Presidential Candidates (Box 11)
    - Publications, 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Publications for Trustees (Box 12)
    - Religious Affairs (Box 12)
    - Siedman, William (Box 12)
    - Staff Appointments (Box 12)
    - Underneath the Arches (newsletter) (Box 12)
    - The Valley View (Box 12)
    - Zumberge, James, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Grosse Ile Nutritional Investigation (Box 12)
  - Growth Charts and Pamphlets (Box 12)
  - H (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
  - Harvard Dental Infirmary for Children (Box 12)
  - Health Careers (Box 12)
  - Health Museum in Cleveland (Box 12)
  - Hidden Hunger (Box 12)
  - Highland View Hospital (Box 12)
  - Hoerr, Norman L. (Box 12)
  - Holy Family and St. Joseph Orphanages Nutritional Study (Box 12)
  - Home Economics, National Council of Administrators (Box 12)
  - Hoobler, Dr. B. Raymond, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Hoobler, Madge Sibley Memorial Guest House (Box 12)
  - Hoobler, Dr. Sibley (Box 12)
  - Human Biology (Box 12)
  - Hunscher, Dr. Helen A. (Box 12)
  - Illinois, University of (Box 12)
  - Institute of Nutrition of Central America and Panama Institute of Public Health Nutrition (Box 12)
  - International Committee for Standardization in Human Biology (Box 13)
  - Iota Sigma Pi, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Iowa State College (Box 13)
  - Iowa State University (Box 13)
  - J (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry (Box 13)
  - Jury Duty-Ann Arbor (Box 13)
  - K (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
  - Kelly, Harriet (Box 13)
  - Kleiner, Dr. Israel (Box 13)
  - Knapp, Dr. Pauline W. (Box 13)
  - Kresge Historical Library in Child Development and Family Life (Box 13)
  - Kresge-Hooker Scientific Library 1942-1960, 8 folders (Box 13)
  - Kriss, Dr. Max (Box 13)
  - L (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
  - Lewis, Dr. Howard B. (Box 13)
  - Ma-Mel (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
  - Mem-Mz (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
  - M & R Dietetic Laboratory (Box 13)
  - McCollum, Dr. E.V. (Box 13)
  - Mack, Dr. Pauline B. 1935-1954, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Margarine Manufacturers, National Association of (Box 13)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital (Metabolic Studies) (Box 13)
  - Maynard, Dr. L.A. (Box 13)
  - Mayo Clinic (Box 13)
  - Medical Woman's Journal (Box 14)
  - Mellanby, Sir Edward and Lady May (Box 14)
  - Merrill-Palmer School (later Institute)
    (1982 accession)
    - Annual Reports 1958-1964 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence
      - 1928-1958 (Box 14)
      - 1960-1973 (Box 14)
    - Courses
      - 1959 (Box 14)
      - 1965-1968 (Box 14)
      - Special (Box 14)
    - Eleventh Growth Symposium (Box 14)
    - Forms (Box 14)
    - Historical Library in Child Development and Family Life 1961-1969, 6 folders (Box 14)
    - Infant Growth Conference 1958-1961, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Infant Growth, teaching of (Box 14)
    - Merrill-Palmer Institute 1970 (Box 14)
    - Papers, Articles, and Pamphlets
      - 1927-1955 (Box 14)
      - 1957-1975 (Box 14)
    - Recognition Fund Committee (Box 14)
    - Reorganization Proposals (Box 14)
    - Research Committee (Box 14)
    - Rioux, Dr. J. William (Box 14)
    - Usdan, Michael D. (Box 14)
  - Merrill-Palmer School (later Institute)
    (2nd accession)
    - Announcement of Courses (Box 29)
    - Clippings (Box 29)
    - Correspondence 1923-1969 (Box 29)
    - Editorials in Journal of American Medical Association about work of School (Box 29)
    - Educational Materials (Box 29)
    - Evaluation Forms (Box 29)
    - Nursery School (Box 29)
    - Publications (Box 29)
    - Publications written by Icie Macy Hoobler (Box 29)
    - Reports (Box 29)
  - Merrill-Palmer Seminars
    - Food and Nutrition (Box 15)
    - 1959-1960
      - Appraisal of Physiological Status in Relation to Health and Growth (Box 15)
      - Lecture I, Life-Growth-Nutrition (Box 15)
      - Lecture II, Human Life Studies (Box 15)
      - Lecture III, The Frontier of Human Welfare (Box 15)
      - Lecture IV, Physical Measurements in Relation to Physiologic Growth (Box 15)
      - Lecture V, Physical, Physiological, Clinical, and Nutritional Individuality (Box 15)
      - Lectures VI and VII (Box 15)
      - Lecture VIII, Physical Anthropology (Box 15)
      - Lecture IX, The Mosaic of Physical and Chemical Growth (Box 15)
      - Lecture X, Health (Box 15)
    - 1960-1961, Teaching of Infant Development (Box 15)
    - 1961 Nutrition and Physiological Growth (Box 15)
    - 1964 Changing Perspectives in Human Development (Box 15)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 15)
    - 1966, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - 1967, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Changing Perspectives of Human Development 1968, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Biosocial Implications of World Hunger and Malnutrition 1969, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Metabolism
    - Child Metabolism
      - Correspondence (Box 15)
      - Notes and Data (Box 15)
      - Working Material (Box 15)
    - Metabolism and Bone Density (Box 15)
    - Metabolism and Emotions
      - Application of Computer to Physiological and Emotional Relations (Box 15)
      - Emotions vs. Metabolism (Box 15)
      - Metabolic Adaptations to Emotional Disturbances, Report 1958-1960 (Box 15)
      - Suggestions for Papers (Box 15)
  - Methodist Children's Home Society
    - Board of Directors
      - 1945-1956 (Box 15)
      - 1956-1960 (Box 15)
      - 1967-1970 (Box 16)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 16)
      - 1973 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence 1932-1952 (Box 16)
    - Health Committee (Box 16)
    - Pamphlets and Clippings (Box 16)
  - Methodist Children's Village (Box 16)
  - Methods of Evaluating Nutritional Status Conference 1941
    - Notes (Box 16)
    - Record of Proceedings, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Michigan Academy of Arts, Letters and Science
    - Bulletins, Newsletters
      - 1959, 1968-1970 (Box 16)
      - 1971-1973 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence
      - 1939-1953 (Box 16)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 16)
      - 1958 (Box 16)
  - Michigan Council of State College Presidents (Box 16)
  - Michigan Department of Health
    - 1939-1949 (Box 16)
    - 1950-1956, 1960-1962 (Box 16)
  - Michigan Department of Social Welfare, Sub-Committee on Health Services for the Child Welfare Agencies 1952 (Box 16)
  - Michigan History (Box 16)
  - Michigan Societies and Associations (Box 16)
  - Michigan State College (Box 16)
  - Michigan's First Governor's Conference on Libraries 1962 (Box 16)
  - Minnesota, University of (Box 16)
  - Mitchell, Dr. Harold H. (Box 16)
  - Mitchell, Dr. Helen S. (Box 16)
  - Modern Medicine Magazine (Box 16)
  - Morgan, Dr. Agnes Fay (Box 16)
  - Morse, Miss Elba (Box 16)
  - Mother's Milk Bureau
    - Correspondence 1946-1957 (Box 16)
    - Papers, Notes, Pamphlets (Box 16)
  - N (miscellaneous) (Box 16)
  - National Association for Nursery Education (Box 16)
  - National Broadcasting Company (Box 16)
  - National Council on Hunger and Malnutrition in the United States, Action Report 1970 (Box 16)
  - National Dairy Council (Box 17)
  - National Health Assembly (Box 17)
  - National Institute of Health (Box 17)
  - National Organizations for Children and Youth
    - 1961, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - 1962 (Box 17)
    - 1964 (Box 17)
    - 1966 (Box 17)
    - 1967 (Box 17)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 17)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 17)
  - National Organization for Women
    - 1973 (Box 17)
    - 1974-1976 (Box 17)
  - National Research Council
    - Committee on Maternal and Child Feeding
      - Composition of Women's and Cow's Milk (Box 17)
      - Correspondence 1928-1953, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Memoranda to Members (Box 17)
      - Minutes (Box 17)
      - Reports, statements, etc. (Box 17)
    - Food and Nutrition Board
      - Committee on Food Habits (Box 29)
      - Correspondence 1940-1953, 10 folders (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 29)
    - Nutrition Surveys
      - Clinical Diagnosis in Nutrition Surveys (Box 29)
      - Nutrition Surveys in Relation to Professional Training in Schools of Medicine and Public Health (Box 29)
      - The Objectives and Demonstrated Value of Nutrition Surveys (Box 29)
      - The Role of Health Departments in Nutrition Surveys and Appraisal (Box 29)
      - The Role of Surveys in Community Nutrition Programs (Box 29)
    - Proceedings
      - 1949 1954 (Box 29)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 29)
      - 1957, 1959-1961 (Box 29)
  - Nayar, Dr. Sushila (Box 18)
  - New York Academy of Sciences (Box 18)
  - Norton, William J. (Box 18)
  - Nutrition
    - Fifth International Congress on Nutrition 1960, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Food and Nutrition, U.S. Department of Agriculture (Box 18)
    - National Nutrition Policy (Box 18)
    - Nutrition Bulletin, Church World Service (Box 18)
  - Nutrition Foundation, Inc.
    - Correspondence and Miscellaneous 1942-1959, 9 folders (Box 18)
    - Food Industries Advisory Committee 1949-1954 (Box 18)
    - Grants to Children's Fund of Michigan 1946-1955 (Box 18)
    - Human Milk Study
      - Cornell University, 1942-1945, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - University of Pittsburgh 1942-1944 (Box 18)
    - King, Dr. C. Glenn (Box 18)
    - Pamphlets and Booklets (Box 18)
    - Scientific Advisory Committee
      - 1953 (Box 18)
      - 1955-1956, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Transcripts of Talks 1950-1951 (Box 18)
  - Nutrition (miscellaneous)
    - Nutrition in Industry (Box 18)
    - Nutrition in Medicine, Dentistry and Industry, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Symposium on Clinical Nutrition (Box 18)
  - O (miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Omicron Nu (Box 18)
  - Oregon State College (Box 18)
  - P (miscellaneous) (Box 18)
  - Pediatrics Congress (Box 18)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 18)
  - Philosophy of Science (Box 18)
  - Pi Beta Phi (Box 18)